elephant.com 2017-01-23

# Elephant Auto Insurance | Privacy & Security

Elephant Insurance Company (Elephant) collects customer information to help us to serve you better. We are committed to protecting your privacy by maintaining and using this information responsibly. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we collect, the use and disclosure of personal information we collect, as well as how we protect that information. By visiting our website or providing your information to us, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. By providing your telephone number, you authorize Elephant and its representatives to contact you at that number regarding the sale of insurance products and services. You agree that you may be contacted in person, by recorded message or by the use of automated dialing equipment. You are not required to provide your telephone number to receive a quote.

#### What information do you collect about me?

Elephant collects information about you to quote and service your insurance policy. The information we collect that identifies you is known as “nonpublic personal information” (NPPI), because it personally identifies you and is not otherwise available lawfully through a public information source. We commonly collect several types of this information from the following sources: 

Application Information: This is information provided by you, the consumer, on your application either by phone or online. We may also obtain it from outside sources. It includes your name, street address, phone number, e-mail address, driver’s license number, Social Security number, date of birth, gender, marital status, vehicle information, and information about other drivers.

It is vitally important that you inform us of any change to your application information in a timely manner. It not only allows us to ensure that we meet your changing insurance needs, but it assists us in protecting your privacy. It is especially important that you notify us about changes in your contact information, as we periodically may need to speak to you or send you information regarding your policy. To provide updates, please contact one of our customer service specialists at 1-877-218-7865. 

Consumer Report Information: We obtain this information from third party consumer reporting agencies. It includes your driving record, claims history with other insurers, and credit report information. Credit report information is used to develop an insurance score. This credit-based insurance score does not affect your financial credit score. The information is kept by the consumer reporting agencies and disclosed by them to others as permitted by law. Consumer reporting agencies may be contacted during underwriting, processing claims, investigations, to service your account, and other purposes as permitted by law.

Transaction information: This is information about your transactions with Elephant. It includes your insurance coverages, limits, rates, and payment and claims history. It also includes information that we require for billing and payment.

Website information: This information is unique to Internet transactions. It includes the website that linked you to ours, your computer operating system, and the pages you viewed on our site. Some websites, including ours, may also store “cookies” on your computer. Cookies collect technical data such as your Internet protocol (IP) address, operating system, and session ID. They may also save certain information entered by you.

#### Why do you ask for my e-mail address?

When you get a quote or purchase a policy, we collect your e-mail address so that we may send periodic emails to you of both promotional and transactional nature. If you no longer wish to receive promotional email communications from us, you may opt-out by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each communication or by contacting us at customerservice@elephant.com.

####  Notice of Financial Information Collection and Disclosure Practices

Elephant collects financial information in connection with insurance transactions. Financial information is any personal information about an individual other than medical information. This information is used to keep our rates competitive for customers. As part of the NPPI, financial information is collected and disclosed as described above. As described in this notice, this information is restricted and protected and is disclosed only when allowed by law. Examples of disclosures would include reporting information as permitted by law to a Consumer Reporting Agency, or information transmitted to a third party in connection to an insurance transaction. Furthermore, by agreements, these third parties will maintain the confidentiality of this information and not disclose it unless permitted by law.

####  How will you share this information about me?

Elephant reserves the right to disclose nonpublic personal information (NPPI) it collects to third parties. Without prior authorization, we will share information about you only as permitted by law. However, as permitted by law, disclosures of NPPI we have collected may be made to our affiliates and partners when deemed necessary to business operations. Disclosures may also lawfully be made to prevent, detect, or investigate criminal activity, fraud, and misrepresentation.

Disclosures of NPPI are made only when required to provide insurance claims or customer service, prevent fraud, perform research or comply with the law. Examples of potential recipients to whom your NPPI may be disclosed include: claims representatives, underwriters, service providers, consumer reporting agencies, other insurance agencies, law enforcement, and government agencies. These parties may disclose the information to others as permitted by law. For example, consumer reporting agencies may disclose transaction information received from us to other insurance companies with whom you do business.

####  How do you protect my information?

Elephant restricts access to your NPPI to our employees and others we feel must use it to provide our products and services. We require those individuals with access to your customer information to protect it and keep it confidential. Their use of the information is limited by law, our employee Code of Ethics, and written agreements where appropriate. We also maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable regulatory security standards to protect your information.

####  How can I opt out?

Elephant reserves the right to disclose NPPI to third parties. You have the opportunity to notify us at any time that you wish to opt out of the disclosures described in this Privacy Notice before any disclosure is made to a third party. You can partially or completely opt out of disclosures. If you do not choose to opt out and allow sharing of your information when necessary, you do not need to take any action. If you choose to opt out and prefer that we do not share your information except as otherwise permitted by law, you may notify us of your decision by submitting your name and policy numbers in either of the following methods:

  * Send an email to CustomerService@elephant.com. In the subject line, please include the phrase, “Do not share my information”.
  * Send a written request not to share your information to the following address: Elephant Insurance Company, Attn: Do Not Share My Information, P.O. Box 5005, Glen Allen, VA 23058-5005

Joint applicants may opt out jointly, or submit opt out notices individually. If you have previously submitted an opt out notice to Elephant, you need not submit another notice as long as you continue to be a customer under the policy numbers you designated in the opt out. An opt out notice is effective until revoked by the customer.. If you cease to be a customer of Elephant, we will continue to protect your privacy and acknowledge any opt out notices you provided in regards to those inactive policies.

####  How can I review information you have about me?

To review credit information used in developing your insurance score or to review non-credit information (accidents or violations), please contact the consumer reporting agency listed below:

For Credit:  
Equifax Information Services  
PO Box 740256  
Atlanta, GA 30347  
Phone: 1-800-685-1111  

For Non-Credit:  
LexisNexis Consumer Center  
PO Box 105108  
Atlanta, GA 30348-5108  
Phone: 800-456-6004  
Email: consumer.center@lexisnexis.com

Upon review of your report(s), you may want to challenge the accuracy of specific information. Depending on your request, either agency can assist you with the process of disputing or correcting information on these reports. Their role is to supply information to Elephant Insurance Company, which Elephant reviews for assistance in making underwriting decisions. 

You have a right to know the contents of any NPPI that Elephant has collected about you, and to review or obtain copies of that information. You also have a right to request that we correct, amend, or delete any information you feel is in error. To review information Elephant has collected concerning you, send a written request to:

Elephant Insurance Company   
Attn: Privacy Policy   
PO Box 5005   
Glen Allen, VA 23058-5005

You must describe the kind of information you want to review and state that your request is in response to this Privacy Policy. Please include your full name, address, and policy number (if applicable), and either your date of birth, driver’s license number, or social security number. Within 30 business days, we will describe what is available and how you may request corrections. We will also identify the companies that have provided consumer report information about you.

These rights do not extend to information collected in connection with or in reasonable anticipation of a claim, civil or criminal proceeding, or to specific items of privileged information when an applicant or policy holder is suspected of fraud, material misrepresentation, or material nondisclosure. 

####  How can I correct information you have about me?

To correct information about you, send a written request as described above, explaining your desired correction. Within 30 business days, we will either make the requested correction or tell you why we did not make the requested correction. We cannot correct consumer report information, such as your credit report. To correct consumer report information, you must contact the consumer reporting agency that provided it.

If we make the requested correction, we will notify you in writing. If required by law, we will also notify others who may have given or received it from us. If we refuse to make the requested correction, you may file with us a concise statement about why you object, including the information you believe to be incorrect. Your statement will then become part of your file. It will be sent to the same persons to whom we would send a copy of any correction or change.

####  Is there additional information for Website visitors?

Yes. When you visit our website, we may use the information we collect to provide services to you. We may also use website information to help understand what you may want in order to enhance your online experience. For example, if you start an insurance quote on our website, but decide to finish it later, we will save your information so you may resume the process from the point where you left off.

We also use website information to analyze use of our website. Information that does not identify you may be used for marketing purposes. We advertise on other companies’ websites. These sites may use technology (such as cookies) to transmit non-personally identifiable information about you to us or our service providers. We may use this information to analyze our marketing efforts.

We may use advertising companies to display our ads on other websites. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information about your visits to websites. In addition, we may share website usage information with these companies to manage advertisements, or for market research purposes.

You can choose to have your browser warn you each time a cookie is delivered to it, or you can choose to reject all cookies delivered through your browser. However, if you choose to reject cookies, features that make your web experience run more smoothly may not be available.

Third Party Analytics. We have engaged Inspectlet to analyze the activities of visitors to this website, and Inspectlet’s authorized use of cookies and other tracking technologies enable it to have access to Personal Information of visitors to this website. Such access to and use of Personal Information by Inspectlet is governed by Inspectlet’s Privacy Policy [https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy].

#### Review of anonymous data from Google Analytics

We are committed to ensuring that our website contains content that is valuable and useful to our customers and potential customers who visit. To assist us in this, we have implemented the Google analytics demographics and interest reporting features on our website. These tools allow us to review anonymous data regarding the gender, age, and interests of website visitors and adapt our website content to better reflect their needs. Although this information is collected through your Google ad settings, it is not provided to us in a personally-identifiable format. This means we cannot identify what information is about you, and we will not try to figure it out.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Google Ad settings](https://www.google.ca/settings/ads) or through the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

#### Links to other websites

To enhance your online experience, our website may include links to other sites outside our family of brands. Those websites will have their own privacy policies that you may wish to review. Elephant has no responsibility for these linked websites, outside of our family of brands.

####  Modification of our privacy policy

We reserve the right to modify our privacy policy at any time, when permitted by law. A revised privacy notice will be provided to you when any material change occurs, and you will be given further opportunity to opt out. As required by law, we will notify you of our privacy and information practices regularly.
